It's a lost cow.
（電話:忍野(おしの)）
“迷(まよ)い牛(うし)”
It has to be a lost cow, doesn't it?
迷い牛だろ そりゃ
When you write snail with kanji, you write the kanji for cow, right?
カタツムリを漢字で書きゃ
牛って入っているでしょうが
Take the first symbol from whirlpool, change the water radical into an insect one, add cow, and you have snail.
渦巻の渦の
さんずいを虫偏に変えて
それで牛 蝸牛(かたつむり)だよ
SNAIL
COW
You hear of countless types of things that will confuse people, but...
人を迷わせる類いの怪異(かいい)は
そりゃ数えきれないくらいに
いっぱい いるけれど
in your situation, and that bit you said about a snail, it definitely has to be a lost cow, right?
そのタイプで蝸牛だっていうなら
迷い牛で間違いないでしょ
It's time to talk about spring vacation.
It was spring holiday.
I was attacked by a vampire.
By a beautiful demon.
I was attacked by a demon so beautiful blood froze in my veins.
As a result, I
became a vampire.
The one who saved me from that hell was, a
passerby, that is, Oshino Meme.
And, I returned to humanity.
Well, it's not an important story.
It's not a happy ending at all.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
But this matter is over, already resolved.
The only remnants of it are that I have to have my blood drunk every month
and that at these times my eyesight surpasses a human's.
These have already become something like my personal traits
since they're things that aren't too hard to face for the rest of my life.
And yet...
My situation was yet lucky.
Because, in the end, it just took me a spring holiday.
For instance,
Senjougahara is different.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
She, for over two years, was forced
to bear with her inconvenient body.
This inconvenience, that interfered her freedom.
I wonder what are
two years of  hell like...
wrapping
circle
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
What sort of feeling would it be -- over two years of hell?
So that's why Senjougahara, unlike herself, admirably,
felt more obligation to me than necessary.
I should have expected it probably.
Putting aside the inconveniences that bound her body,
but a result that she was able to solve the inconveniences of her soul
should have been a memorable,
difficult achievement for her.
Typeface used for images: HGP mincho B
Mayoi Snail, Part Two
Episode 4
STOP
（戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)）この辺り
It's around here.
（阿良々木(あららぎ)）は？
Huh?
It should be around here: the house where I lived.
（戦場ヶ原）
この辺りだったのよ
私の住んでた家
bargain sale location
STOP
House? Isn't this just a road?
（阿良々木）家って… 道じゃん
STOP
District reshuffling.
（戦場ヶ原）区画整理ね
Not even a year has passed and already it has become like this.
たかだか１年足らずだというのに
何てことかしら
（八九寺(はちくじ)）うっ
We already sold it, and I didn't really think the house would remain...
（戦場ヶ原）売っちゃったわけだし
家が残っているとは
思っていなかったけれど
And yet, this is quite depressing.
これは さすがに結構ブルーだわ
Yeah, isn't it?
（阿良々木）
まあ そりゃ そうだよな
（戦場ヶ原）ハア
Time is wasted on something that can't be helped.
どうしようもないことで
時間を取らせてしまったわね
Let's go, Araragi-kun.
行きましょうか 阿良々木くん
Are you done already?
（阿良々木）え… もう いいのか？
Done.
（戦場ヶ原）いいのよ
I see.
あっそ　じゃ 行くぞ 八九寺
Let's go, Hachikuji.
It's about time you let go of my leg, Hachikuji.
（阿良々木）
いい加減に僕の足から離れろよ
八九寺
It's difficult for me to walk.
歩きにくいんだよ
Say something. Don't be so quiet.
何か言えよ 黙ってないで
It's not like I want to be stuck to your disgusting legs like a louse!
（八九寺）
私だって 阿良々木さんの
いかつい脚になんて
しがみつきたくなんか ありません
You're mean! I'm reporting this to the PTA!
ひどいです！ ＰＴＡに訴えます！
The PTA?
へえ ＰＴＡに…
The PTA is a very incredible organization, you know.
ＰＴＡは
ものすごい組織なんですよ
A minor like you with no influence: your life hangs in the balance!
阿良々木さんみたいな
何の権力も持たない
未成年の 一市民なんて
With a single finger, they'll go "pop" and it'll be over!
指先ひとつで ポポイのポイです！
A single finger, huh? That's pretty scary.
指先ひとつか　そりゃ 怖いな
By the way, Hachikuji, what does PTA stand for?
ところで 八九寺
ＰＴＡとは何の略なんだ？
Question
What does
PTA
stand for?
That's...
え？ それは…
PTA is the abbreviation of Parent Teacher Association.
（戦場ヶ原）ＰＴＡというのは
Parent Teacher Associationの略よ
That means it's an association for parents and teachers.
親と教師の会という意味ね
It can also stand for the surgical method percutaneous transluminal angioplasty. That's medical jargon.
経皮経管(けいひけいかん)的血管形成術という
医学用語の略でもあるけれど
Magnification
Ulna bone
Radius bone
Carpal bone
Left forearm
Right forearm (X-Ray)
Observation:
Early morning on the fourteenth,
being drunk, was hit by a car.
After being dragged for 1km, finally fell to a ditch.
Magnification
Ulna bone
Radius bone
Carpal bone
Left forearm
Right forearm (X-Ray)
Observation:
Early morning on the fourteenth,
being drunk, was hit by a car.
After being dragged for 1km, finally fell to a ditch.
Medical abbreviation
Percutaneous Transluminal
Angioplasty
I doubt that's the answer you were looking for.
阿良々木くんが そんなものを
求めているとは思えないから
Under these circumstances, the Parent Teacher Association should be the correct explanation.
この場合は
親と教師の会で正解でしょう
My, aren't you knowledgeable.
へえ 戦場ヶ原 さすがに博学だな
It's you who's ignorant and incompetent, Araragi-kun.
（戦場ヶ原）
あなたが浅学非才なだけよ
阿良々木くん
The word "ignorant" has a nice ring to it, so I don't mind being called that,
語呂がいいから
浅学と言われるのには文句はないが
but "incompetent" is going just a bit too far...
しかし 非才は
この場合 余計では？
Is that so?
（戦場ヶ原）
そうかしら じゃあ
悲惨と言いかえておくわ
Then I'll just use "pathetic" next time.
By the way, Hachikuji...
時に八九寺
What is it, Araragi-san?
何でしょう 阿良々木さん
What exactly is the place that this address is referring to?
（阿良々木）
この住所の場所には
一体 何があるんだ？
（八九寺）フーンだ
I'm not telling.
話しません　黙秘権を行使します
I choose to remain silent.
I won't take you there if you don't tell me.
教えねえと連れてってやんねえぞ
I didn't ask for your help. I can go alone.
（八九寺）
別に頼んでません
１人で行けます
But you lost your way.
（阿良々木）でも お前 迷子だろ？
So what?
（八九寺）だったら何ですか！
いや 八九寺 あのな
後学のために教えてやるけれど
Hachikuji, umm...
For the sake of younger generations, I'll tell you that relying on others is okay.
そういうときは
誰かを頼ればいいんだよ
Sure, that's fine for you, with your low self-esteem.
自分に自信が持てない
阿良々木さん辺りは
そうすればいいです
Go ahead and wear yourself out relying on others,
気の済むまで
他人を頼ってください
but I don't have a need to do such a thing.
でも私は そんなことを
する必要が ないんです
To me, this is as simple as using an everyday vending machine!
私にとっては この程度
Amami Drink Corporation
日常自販機なんですから！
へえ 定価販売なんだな
Fixed selling price?
O
Cold Drinks
120 Yen
Coin * Return
Vending
Sold out
Amami Drink Corporation
I understand, mistress.
分かりましたよ お嬢様
I beg of thee. Please tell me what may be found at the place indicated by this address.
お願いです この住所の場所に
一体 何があるのか
どうか 私めに教えてくださいませ
Your words are insincere.
言葉に誠意が こもってません
（阿良々木）くっ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Araragi
If she were either of my two sisters, she would have been tricked upon hearing it.
（阿良々木）
妹なら２人とも
この手で確実に落ちるんだが
Looks like methods used to treat stupid kids do not work on her.
八九寺はバカな子供を
あしらうようには いかない
というわけか
Seriously, what should I do?
まったく どうしたものだろう
Mistress, have some allowance.
（阿良々木）
お嬢ちゃん お小遣いをあげよう
Oh, goody! I'll tell you anything!
（八九寺）
きゃっほ〜 何でも話します！
Was an idiot child.
Animation Number 86
I see it's a stupid kid.
（阿良々木）
バカな子供だった
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Water Department
A person named Tsunade-san lives there.
その住所には
綱手(つなで)さんという方が住んでいます
Oh?
（阿良々木）ふ〜ん
What's your relationship?
で どういう知り合いなんだ？
A relative.
（八九寺）親戚です
Relative, I see.
（阿良々木）親戚ね…
At least during Mother's Day you must practice filial piety at home.
母の日くらい
うちで親孝行
してればいいのに
A younger sister that rebukes her stupid older brother.
Animation Number 95
Because you're always like this...
（火憐(かれん)）
兄ちゃんは
そんなことだから
Because of this, no matter how long...
いつまで たっても…
I don't want to be taught a lesson by you.
阿良々木さんに
言われたくは ありません
No, what do you know?
いや お前が何を知ってるんだよ
Somehow, I know.
何となくです
You were the one sitting on a park bench and spacing out this Sunday morning.
阿良々木さんこそ 日曜日の朝から
公園のベンチで
ボーッとしているなんて
That isn't what a normal person would do.
まともな人間のやることとは
思えませんが
No, I was only...
（阿良々木）別に ただの…
Touring.
ツーリングだよ
T
Wheel
ourin
G
Wheel
Tworing?
（八九寺）
ツーリングですか
かっこいいです！
How cool!
Well, I'm actually only using my bicycle.
（阿良々木）
まっ 自転車でだけどな
I see.
（八九寺）
そうですか　ツーリングと言えば
やはりバイクですよね
Speaking of tworing, it should indeed be a motorbike.
What a pity...
とても惜しい感じです
It's because school rules forbid students to take driving tests for motorbike licenses.
（阿良々木）
学校が校則で免許の取得を
禁止しているからな
A
Naoetsu High School
Rules
9th Article
Revision 2009.04.28
* Students are prohibited from
riding two-wheeled motorized vehicles.
buying two-wheeled motorized vehicles.
* Students are prohibited from
getting a license for two-wheeled motorized vehicles.
Those who break the
aforementioned rules
will be punished with
expulsion.
Naoetsu High School Headmaster
Hirobumi Ito.
But regardless, motorbikes are dangerous.
でも どっちみち
バイクは危ないからな
I prefer cars.
僕は車のほうが いいや
エヘッ
I see.
そうですか　でも それですと
But that's fourring.
フォーリングに
なってしまいますよね
This person has amusingly mixed up the meaning of touring.
（阿良々木）
この子 ツーリングのスペルを
かなり面白く勘違いしている
Water Department
By the way, the roads here are really complicated.
でも 本当に ややこしいな
この辺の道
You have some guts to come here alone.
お前 よくこんな所を
１人で来ようと思ったもんだよ
Water Department S
Well, it's not the first time I've been here.
（八九寺）
別に初めてでは ないですから
It isn't? Then how did you get lost?
（阿良々木）
そうなのか？
じゃあ なんで迷うんだよ
District Water Meter
う… 久しぶりだからです
I haven't been here for a long time.
By the way, Arararagi-san...
そういえば あらららぎさんは
You included an extra "ra."
“ら”が１個 多いぞ
Sorry. I stuttered...
（八九寺）失礼 かみました
Don't say my name in such a disgusting way...
気分の悪い かみ方
してんじゃねえよ
It can't be helped. Anybody will have times when they say something wrong.
（八九寺）しかたがありません
誰だって言い間違いを
することくらいは あります
Don't tell me that you've never stuttered before.
それとも阿良々木さんは
Use button
at night
生まれてから 一度も
かんだことがないと言うのですか
I can't say I haven't,
（阿良々木）ないとは言わないが
but it never happened when I said another person's name.
少なくとも
人の名前をかんだりはしないよ
Use button
at night
（八九寺）では
Then...
Say "Basugasubakuhatsu" thrice.
バスガス爆発と
３回言ってください
That isn't a person's name.
（阿良々木）
それ 人の名前じゃないじゃん
It is a person's name.
いえ 人の名前です
知り合いに３人ほどいます
I know at least three people with that name.
That's why it's safe to say that it's a fairly common name.
ですから むしろ かなり
一般的な名前であると思われます
Basugasubakuhatsu, Basugasubakuhatsu, Basugasubakuhatsu...
（阿良々木）
バスガス爆発 バスガス爆発
バスガス爆発
The creature that devours dreams is...?
夢を食べる動物は？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Baku?
バク？
Wrong answer.
ブブー はずれです
Creatures that eat dreams are...
夢を食べる動物 それは
humans.
人間ですよ
Don't act smart!
うまいこと言ってんじゃねえよ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hey, Araragi-kun.
（戦場ヶ原）ねえ 阿良々木くん
Huh?
（阿良々木）ん？
Could you tell me the address again?
（戦場ヶ原）
もう一度 住所 教えてくれる？
Okay, let me take a look.
（阿良々木）
まあ いいけど　えっと
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It seems like we've passed here before.
どうも行き過ぎてしまったようね
Eh? Have we?
（阿良々木）え… そうなの？
If you want to blame me, go ahead.
（戦場ヶ原）
責めたければ
好きなだけ責めなさい
No. I won't blame you for such a minor thing.
（阿良々木）
いや この程度のことで
責めたりは しないよ
（戦場ヶ原）そう
I see.
SCHOOL
Children Crossing
Why are you so afraid of Senjougahara?
（阿良々木）
お前 なんで そこまで
戦場ヶ原のことビビッてんだ？
She seems to hate me.
（八九寺）
どうも 私は嫌われているようです
I can feel the strong aura coming from her body saying, "What a hindrance! Get lost somewhere!"
邪魔だ どこかに消えろという
強い意思を感じます
Not to that extent, right?
（阿良々木）
さすがに そんなことは
ないとは思うが
Hey, Senjougahara.
（阿良々木）なあ 戦場ヶ原
What?
（戦場ヶ原）何よ
Do you hate kids?
（阿良々木）
お前って 子供 嫌いなの？
I hate them. I really do.
（戦場ヶ原）嫌いね 大嫌い
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
They should all die.
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
１人残らず
死ねばいいのに
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Because I totally don't know how to get close to a kid.
（戦場ヶ原）
どう接していいのか
全く分からないもの
It was during middle school, I think.
中学生のときだったかしらね
デパートで買い物をしていたら
I came out of the department store after buying some things and bumped into a kid around 7 years old.
私 ７歳くらいの子供に
ぶつかってしまったの
Ah, and he cried?
（阿良々木）
ああ それで泣かれちゃったとか？
No, it's not the problem of crying.
（戦場ヶ原）
いえ そうじゃなくてね
I said to the 7 year old kid at that time...
私 そのとき
その７歳くらいの子供に対して
こう言っちゃったのよ
"Are you alright?
Are you hurt?
I'm terribly sorry."
"Are you all right?"
“大丈夫ですか
ケガは ありませんか”
"Are you hurt?"
"I'm terribly sorry."
“ごめんなさい
申し訳ありません”って
Because I really didn't know how to face kids, I was shocked and made a mistake.
子供相手に どうしていいのか
分からなくなって
気が動転してしまったのね
But to actually make me bow down and grovel... I was shocked.
だけど だからって 私が
あんなに下手(したて)に出てしまうだなんて
それが 私はショックでショックで
From then on, those existences called "children," be they humans or otherwise,
以来 子供と呼ばれるものは
人間であれ何であれ
I have hated and been cautious of.
憎しみをもって向かうように
心掛けているわ
I understand her reasoning,
but I don't understand her feelings.
By the way, Araragi-kun...
ところで 阿良々木くん
What?
（阿良々木）どうした？
It seems like we've gone too far again.
（戦場ヶ原）
どうも また
行き過ぎてしまったみたい
Eh, the residence?
（阿良々木）
えっ 住所を？ ２回目だぞ おい
This is the second time, hey.
If you are capable, please blame me however you like.
責められるものなら
いくらでも責めてみなさい
No, I won't blame you over such a small thing...
（阿良々木）
いや この程度のことで
責めたり…
って あれ？
Eh, Senjougahara.
戦場ヶ原 何か さっきと
セリフが微妙に変わってないか？
Didn't you already say that earlier?
Ah, is that so?
（戦場ヶ原）あら そうかしら
What's wrong?
（阿良々木）何だよ あっ そっか
Ah, right. Didn't you say it's due to district reshuffling that you lost your way?
区画整理が どうとかって
言ってたな　そのせいか
No, it's not.
（戦場ヶ原）
いえ そういうことでは ないのよ
It's not like all the roads from before are gone.
昔の道が完全になくなっている
わけではないから
It isn't because of the structure that we're lost.
構造的に迷うわけが ないのよ
What are you doing?
（阿良々木）何をしているんだ？
I plan to use the GPS navigation system.
ＧＰＳのナビゲーションシステムを
使ってみようと思うの
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Oh?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
ふ〜ん
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（ピピッ ピピッ）
（戦場ヶ原）え…
Eh?
What's the matter?
（阿良々木）どうした？
All of a sudden, it's out of range.
（戦場ヶ原）
急に圏外になってしまったわ
This is...
これは…
I guess this won't work.
（八九寺）
多分 無理だと思います
Ah?
I can't find it no matter how many times I walk here.
（八九寺）
何度 行っても
たどり着けないんですから
（阿良々木）
八九寺？
Hachikuji?
I'm always walking toward nowhere.
（八九寺）
私は いつまでも
たどり着けないんです
I can't reach my mother's side.
お母さんの所には
たどり着けません
Because I'm a lost snail...
私は蝸牛の迷子ですから
Snail
Animation Number 221
Now, Commercial Break
Bakemonogatari episode four Mayoi snail part two first half finished
(TV Broadcast Time)
We, who couldn't find the destination no matter what, consulted Oshino.
（阿良々木）
どうしても目的地に
たどり着けない僕らは
忍野に相談することにした
Rouhaku Park
A
Bike Parking
Arrange
tidily
Do you know where it is?
場所は分かるのか？
何なら やっぱり僕が行こうか
If you're not sure, then maybe I should go.
To have you worried that my memory will reach your level... I'm not the least happy about it.
（戦場ヶ原）
阿良々木くんの お粗末な記憶力と
同じレベルで心配してもらっても
私はうれしくも何ともないわ
I should say that I'm extremely depressed.
むしろ悲しくなってくる
くらいだもの
Is that so?
そうですか
（戦場ヶ原）ていうか
By the way...
Whisper
Animation Number 233A
Don't leave me alone with that child.
その子と
２人きりになんて しないで
Whisper
Animation Number 233A
Animation Number 233H
A
Bike Parking
Arrange
tidily
After hearing my strange exchange with Senjougahara,
（阿良々木）
僕と戦場ヶ原が遭った
怪異の話をしてから
she seems to have tensed up again.
何だか また
警戒されちゃってるんだよな
Say, you mentioned something about your mother, right?
お前さ あのとき
お母さんって言ってたよな
Isn't that "Tsunade" person a relative?
Tsunade
Animation Number 243B
綱手っていうのは
親戚の家じゃ
なかったのか？
Hachikuji-chan, I will treat you to ice cream next time, so could you come closer?
八九寺ちゃん 今度 アイスクリーム
食べさせてあげるから
もうちょっと
こっちに近づいてこない？
Let's go!
（八九寺）行きます！
Then, coming back to what I said just now, your mother is...
（阿良々木）
それで さっきの話だけれど
お母さんって？
A mother is also considered a type of relative, right?
母親だって親戚のうちでしょう
Well, that may be correct, but...
いや そりゃ そうだけどさ
Besides, even if you say "mother," regretfully it isn't like that anymore.
それに お母さんといっても
残念なことに もう
お母さんじゃありませんから
Ah...
Tsunade was my surname before third grade.
（八九寺）
綱手というのは３年生までの
私の名前でした
After living with my father, it was changed to Hachikuji.
お父さんに引き取られて
八九寺へと名字が
変わっちゃいましたけれど
Seriously? I actually put on an adult look, saying things like, "Practice filial piety."
あっちゃ〜
偉そうに年上ぶって
親孝行しろよとか
言っちゃったよ 僕
No, I didn't come here just because it's Mother's Day.
（八九寺）
いえ 別に今日が母の日だから
ということでは ないです
I'll head toward my mother's place whenever I get the chance.
お母さんの家は機会さえあれば
いつでも来たい場所ですから
I see.
なるほどね
But, no matter how many times I search for it, I still can't find it.
だけど 何度訪ねても
いつでも たどり着けませんけれど
That's when you met that snail?
（阿良々木）
そのとき蝸牛に遭ったってわけか
I'm not too sure if I have met it.
（八九寺）
遭ったというか
よく分かりませんが
You look as if you've had many painful encounters.
（阿良々木）
お前も いろいろ大変だったんだな
ガウ！
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Ouch, ouch! You damned imp! What are you doing?!
（阿良々木）痛(い)って！
いきなり何すんだ このガキ
Ouch, it hurts. It hurts like hell!
（阿良々木）痛い！ 痛い 痛い
痛いって！
てい！
HIT
Unripened Fruit
Animation Number 279
HIT
Ah... No, I can't seem to laugh it out.
いや 笑えないな
A repeated victory will lead to one feeling empty.
２回目以降となっちまうと
ただ むなしいだけのもんなんだな
勝利なんて
There stood a high school boy, who for selfish reasons...
（阿良々木）
小学生女子を２回も殴りつけ
失神させた挙句に
had twice beaten an elementary school girl unconscious, and had gotten all nihilistically
ニヒルを気取って たそがれている
男子高校生の姿が そこにはあった
worked up about it.
Actually, that's still me.
ていうか それも僕だった
wound
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Your expression is really scary, Araragi-kun.
（羽川(はねかわ)）
怖い顔になってるよ 阿良々木くん
（阿良々木）あ… はっ 羽川？
Ha-Hanekawa.
A look of shock.
（羽川）
びっくりしたみたいな顔になったね
うん まあ
そっちのほうが いいかな
That expression is much better.
どうしたの？
何やってるの こんなとこで
What's wrong? What are you doing here?
I was just killing time.
ちょっと まあ
暇つぶしっていうか
ああ そうなんだ
I see.
I'm also here to kill some time.
私も暇つぶしかな
I can't stay put at home. Sunday is the day I go for walks.
私 家 いづらいからさ
日曜日は散歩の日なのよ
I feel that you worry too much...
（阿良々木）
気 遣い過ぎだと思うけどな
Say, by the way, Araragi-kun.
ねえ ところで阿良々木くん
その子 妹さん？
Is that child your sister?
It's a girl who got lost.
（阿良々木）
えっと 迷子の子だよ
八九寺真宵(まよい)って名前
Her name is Hachikuji Mayoi.
Hachikuji? I heard of it in the Kansai region.
八九寺か
関西圏じゃ よく聞く言葉だね
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
そういえば
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
By the way, the shrine which appeared in The Tales of Shinonome is called...
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hideharu Magota, The Tale of Shinonome
Animation Number 308
「東雲(しののめ)物語」に
出てくる お寺って
確か…
Ah, even though it's said to be that, the kanji is written differently.
あっ あれは でも
漢字が違ったっけ
You sure know everything, don't you?
（阿良々木）
お前は何でも知ってるな
It's not that I know everything. I just know what I know.
何でもは知らないわよ
知ってることだけ
（八九寺）ハア…
Hello, Mayoi-chan. I'm a friend of this boy. My name is Hanekawa Tsubasa.
こんにちは 真宵ちゃん
私 このお兄ちゃんのお友達で
羽川翼(つばさ)っていうんだよ
Don't speak to me. I hate you.
話しかけないでください
あなたのことが嫌いです
It seems that I'm hated.
あれ〜 嫌われるようなこと
しちゃったかな
うり うり
There, there.
Mayoi-chan, you are so cute.
かわいいね 真宵ちゃん
I just want to eat you up!
いや〜ん ホント
食べちゃいたいくらい ウフッ
あっ でもね
But you can't bite this boy's hand all of a sudden, okay?
お兄ちゃんの手 いきなり
かんだりしちゃダメじゃない
Thwack
Here, you should apologize.
ほら ごめんなさいは？
ごっ ごめんなさいでした
阿良々木さん
Sorry, Araragi-san.
（阿良々木）え？
And you can't be like that, okay?
（羽川）
それに 阿良々木くんもダメだよ
（阿良々木）
ダメだよって やっぱ暴力？
What do you mean? You're referring to violence, right?
Violence is naturally wrong.
（羽川）
もちろん暴力もダメだけれどね
But after beating a child, it's not right if you don't explain the reason she was beaten.
でも 子供を たたいたら
たたかれたことを
納得できるだけの理由を
話してあげなくちゃダメ
Speaking to you really has its benefits.
お前と話すとホント勉強になるな
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
By the way, did she lose her way around here?
で 迷子なんだっけ？
この辺なの？
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
If that's the case, I may be able to lead the way.
何なら
案内できると思うけど
Well, Senjougahara just went to find someone...
（阿良々木）えっと いや 今
戦場ヶ原に人を呼びにいって
もらってるところだから
Araragi-kun is together with Senjougahara-san?
（羽川）
あれ 阿良々木くん
戦場ヶ原さんと 一緒だったの？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
A while ago, you asked me about some things regarding Senjougahara-san.
この前 阿良々木くん
戦場ヶ原さんのことについて
私に あれこれ聞いてきたよね
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Ah, I see. That's what it is.
ああ そっか そういうこと
Your imagination will make even the girls who like yaoi admit defeat.
お前の そういう妄想力って
やおい好きの女子も
そこのけだよな
Yaoi? What's that?
やおい？ 何それ
No climax
No ending
Deep meaning
It's an acronym for "No climax, no punch line, deep meaning."
（阿良々木）
“やまナシ おちナシ
意味深長”の頭文字だ
Sounds like you're lying.
（羽川）
ウソっぽいね
いいわ 今度 調べてみる
It's okay. I will go and research it.
You really are serious.
（阿良々木）真面目だな
It'd be bad if I've disturbed you guys. I will leave now.
（羽川）
じゃ 邪魔するのもなんだし
私 もう行くね
Sorry to bother you. Say hi to Senjougahara-san for me.
お邪魔しました
戦場ヶ原さんに よろしくね
Like I said, you have misunderstood me.
（阿良々木）だから 誤解してるぞ
I just remembered, Hanekawa. May I ask you something?
あっ そうだ 羽川
一応１つだけ聞かせてくれるか
Do you know where the house of a person called Tsunade-san is?
この辺で綱手さんっていう家
知ってる？
綱手さん？
Tsunade-san?
う〜ん えっと
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I don't know.
（羽川）
いや 知らないわ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
羽川でも
知らないことが あるんだな
There's something that Hanekawa doesn't know?
Didn't I tell you before?
（羽川）言ったでしょ？
It's not that I know everything. It has to be within the boundaries of what I know.
私が知ってるのは
私が知っていることだけなの
As for the others, I don't know anything.
他のことは からきしね
I see.
ああ そう
I'm sorry that I couldn't meet your expectations.
期待に添えず申し訳ないね
It's nothing.
（阿良々木）いやいや
Well this time really is good bye.
（羽川）じゃ 今度こそ バイバイ
（阿良々木）おっ
May 14th
Sunday 14 hours
15 minutes and 30 seconds
was the instant
I got my hands on Senjougahara's mobile number.
Animation Number 355
（阿良々木）
５月14日 日曜日
14時15分30秒—
May 14th, Sunday. 14 hours, 15 minutes, and 30 seconds
was the instant I got my hands on Senjougahara's mobile number.
戦場ヶ原の携帯番号を
入手した瞬間だった
Seriously, I get a rare feeling of laziness on a Sunday morning, and you still come to bother me.
（忍野）
まったく 日曜日の朝の惰眠を
邪魔するなんて
Tsundere-chan's really mean.
ツンデレちゃんは ひどい子だよ
Tsundere-chan? Are you referring to Senjougahara?
（阿良々木）
ツンデレちゃん？
ああ 戦場ヶ原のことか
But by the way, within such a short period of time you were able to encounter such a strange thing.
（電話:忍野）
しっかし よくもまあ
こんな短期間に
そうも いろいろな怪異に
出遭えるもんだよ 阿良々木くんは
The one who encountered it isn't me.
行き遭ったのは僕じゃないよ
Really?
（電話:忍野）
ん？ そうなのかい？
The one who encountered the snail is a child called Hachikuji Mayoi.
（阿良々木）
蝸牛に行き遭ったのは
八九寺真宵って名前の子供だよ
Oh, Hachikuji Mayoi?
（電話:忍野）
ああ 八九寺真宵か
ハハッ なるほどね
見えてきた 見えてきた
I see. Understood, understood.
Hachikuji is the fifth chapter of The Tale of Shinonome.
八九寺つったら あれ
「東雲物語」の第５節
Fifth Chapter of the Tale of Shinonome
Hanekawa also said the same thing.
羽川も そんなこと言ってたな
What's the matter, Tsundere-chan?
（電話:忍野）
ん？ 何だい
ツンデレちゃん
どうした 忍野？
What's wrong, Oshino?
Photograph
Animation
Number
Cut 359
Ah... Hmm...
（電話:忍野）
あ〜 ふ〜ん…
Huh?
（阿良々木）はあ？
Sigh
Animation Number 359
（電話:忍野）
ハア〜 阿良々木くんは
本当に甲斐性なしだな
Araragi-kun is really useless.
Huh? What are you saying?
あ？ 何だよ いきなり
（電話:忍野）
ツンデレちゃんに
こんなに気を遣わせちゃって
To actually make Tsundere-san so worried...
Won't this make her feel responsible?
ツンデレちゃんが
責任を感じちゃってるじゃないか
Ah, to get Senjougahara involved into this, I also feel very sorry.
ああ いや 戦場ヶ原を
巻き込んだのは悪かったと思ってる
（電話:忍野）
そういう意味じゃないよ ったく
I don't mean that. Seriously...
Araragi-kun, your situation together with the President and Tsundere-chan makes it three situations.
阿良々木くん 自分のことと
委員長ちゃんとツンデレちゃんと
Directly after, you became involved in this strange case.
３つ 立て続けに怪異を
解決しちゃったもんだから
That's why you've become arrogant, isn't it?
ちょっと
調子こいちゃったんじゃないの？
I didn't mean it that way.
（阿良々木）
別に そんなつもりはないよ
Furthermore, whenever you encounter a strange thing, there won't always be a person like me by your side.
（電話:忍野）
それに怪異に遭ったとき
僕みたいなのが
そばにいるケースなんて
普通は ありえないんだから
Normally, this would be impossible.
I also don't think a situation like this can be solved through the phone.
まして 電話で
要件を済まされるとは
思いもよらなかったよ
I thought that the situation was simple.
（阿良々木）
まあ 安易だったとは思うよ
And to actually let a ripe, young girl come alone into a strange man's place...
（電話:忍野）
あと 年頃の女の子を１人で
怪しい男が寝泊まりしている場所に
送り込むなんてのも 感心しないよ
I don't think that's proper.
But you wouldn't do anything, right?
でも お前は別に何もしないだろ？
Under normal circumstances, it should be a happy thing to be trusted.
（電話:忍野）
信頼は普通に ありがたいけれど
阿良々木くんが
僕を信頼してくれているほどには
ツンデレちゃんは僕を
But Tsundere-chan isn't like you who has that much trust in me.
信頼してくれているわけじゃ
ないんだから
Wait, wait. I won't do anything.
何もしない 何もしないって！
Put down that stapler, Tsundere-chan.
ホッチキスを構えるのを
やめてくれ ツンデレちゃん
Stapler?
ホッチキス？
（電話:忍野）
ハア びっくりした
Oh, that really frightened me.
Tsundere-chan really is a horrifying Tsundere-chan.
ツンデレちゃんは
怖いツンデレちゃんだったんだな
Eh... Indeed, I'm still not used to speaking on the phone.
えっと じゃあ…
ああ もう やっぱ
電話は苦手だな 話しにくいや
It's hard to say.
What do you mean by that?
話しにくいって そんな…
Then let's do this: I will tell Tsundere-chan the strategy to deal with that lost snail.
（電話:忍野）
じゃあ こうしよう
迷い牛対策は
ツンデレちゃんに伝えておくからさ
In the meantime, you shall stay there.
阿良々木くんは
そこでそのまま じっとしててよ
Strategy?
対策って 人づてで大丈夫なのか
Will it be all right to ask someone to relay it?
Does it require a ceremony like Senjougahara's?
あの戦場ヶ原のときの
あの儀式みたいなのは必要ないのか
No. A snail is not as troublesome as a crab.
（電話:忍野）
ないよ　蝸牛は蟹(かに)ほど厄介じゃない
And it's not a god.
だって神様じゃないもん
If I were to say, it would be a kind of demon or spirit.
お化けだな どっちかって言うと
幽霊とか そっちの類
Spirit?
（阿良々木）幽霊？
By the way, do you happen to know of...
（電話:忍野）
ああ それから
阿良々木くんは知ってるかな
Hachijuuhakkasho of Shikoku and Sanjuusansho of Saigoku?
四国八十八か所とか
西国三十三所とか
I know enough.
（阿良々木）
ああ まあ
それくらいなら さすがに
Hachikuji is of that type.
（電話:忍野）
まあ 八九寺ってのも
いわば その 一種だね
（阿良々木）ふ〜ん
But think. "89" can also be pronounced as "misfortune."
（電話:忍野）
ただ ほらさ
八九って〝やく〞
MISFORTUNE
つまり〝厄〞に
通じちゃうところが
あるじゃない
Because of this sort of explanation, the name Hachikuji will slowly vanish.
そういう解釈が
広がっちゃって
八九寺というくくりは
そのうちに廃れちゃった
（阿良々木）うん
So, it's that sort of connection.
（電話:忍野）
で そういう経緯
歴史を理解したうえで
Once you understand that piece of history, take a look at the name Hachikuji Mayoi.
改めて八九寺真宵って名前を
見るとどうだろう
What do you think?
Do you feel the sharp increase in meaning giving you a headache?
妙に意味ありげで
困っちゃうよね 普通は
Sharp increase in meaning?
意味ありげ？
If you had felt it from the beginning, it would have been good.
（電話:忍野）
阿良々木くんが最初の段階で
それを感じてくれていたなら
よかったんだけれどね
So what if you feel that?
よかったって 何がだよ
I will give the details to Tsundere-chan. Good bye.
（電話:忍野）
じゃ 詳細はツンデレちゃんに
言っとくから
（阿良々木）あ… ああ
Okay.
But it would be nice if Tsundere-chan told you properly.
（電話:忍野）
もっとも ツンデレちゃんが
それを素直に教えてくれれば
いいけどね
Eh?
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
What does he mean?
（阿良々木）どういうことだよ
ハア というわけだ 八九寺
何とか なりそうだぞ
So that's that. Hachikuji.
It seems like there's a way.
From my impression, it doesn't sound like a conversation which found a way.
（八九寺）印象としては
あまり何とか なりそうな
会話では ありませんでしたが
Putting that aside, Araragi-san.
それは ともかく阿良々木さん
何だよ
What?
I'm hungry.
私は おなかが すいていますよ
Bakemonogatari
Snail
Mayoi Snail, Part Two
CONTINUED NEXT TIME
（火憐）火憐だぜ
（月火(つきひ)）月火だよ
I'm Karen.
I'm Tsukihi.
Karen-chan, is it true under the rule of the cherubs, "cos-pos" is forbidden?
火憐ちゃん 剣道の試合じゃ
ガッツポーズ禁止って本当？
What's more scary is that helping is banned too.
（火憐）
そうらしいぜ　応援も禁止だ
And confessing is also forbidden?
（月火）
握手するのも禁止？
Their ban-this-forbid-that match is way messed up.
（火憐）
禁止 禁止
試合後のハグなんて ありえねえ
（月火）
厳しいね
So strict...
Well, they have a weapon with them.
（火憐）
まあ 武器持っちゃってるしな
But for me, their protectors are scarier than weapons.
（月火）
だけど 私に言わせれば
武器よりも防具のほうが怖いよ
Well, like you don't really need protection over there...
（月火）
面 胴 小手
あそこまで守りを固めなくとも
You're so overly safe it's actually scary!
（火憐）
守りすぎて 逆に怖い？
Now then, time for our first nightly quiz!
（月火）
では ここで
初めての予告編クイズ！
It's our fourth time!
（火憐）
４回目だぜ？
Speaking of cellphone ring tones...
（月火）
ケータリングといえば出前ですが
（火憐）
出前だな
It really has that feeling of a cellphone...
（月火）これ 携帯電話っぽいよね
（火憐）んん？
It's forbidden for a phone to ring on the train.
（月火）
そこで 私は携帯電話の使用を
ケータリングと名付けることを
提唱します
It might disturb the other passengers!
（月火）
コラ 電車の中では
ケータリング禁止！
That obviously needs to be prohibited.
（火憐）
そりゃ 禁止だろ
Just please keep your ringtone permanently turned off!
（月火）
いつまでもケータリングしてないで
お風呂 入っちゃいなさい
Please hand out the quiz.
（火憐）
クイズ 出しちゃいなさい
Next time, Mayoi Snail Part 3.
Next Time
Mayoi Snail, Part Three
（火憐･月火）
次回「まよいマイマイ
其ノ参(そのさん)」
Could we see the ringtone of the cellphone?
（月火）
ケータリングでも見れるかな
Can it be seen?
（火憐）
ワンセグもなんだ